Guide to the Francis Fitz Randolph Collection of Incunabula Leaves, 1472-1500
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Guide to the Francis Fitz Randolph Collection of Incunabula Leaves
1472-1500
Randolph, Francis Fitz (collector)
0.5 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Leaves of incunabula collected by Francis Fitz Randolph.
Biographical Note
Francis Fitz Randolph held degrees from Yale and Harvard, was an investment banker who held high-level positions at a number of corporations, and served as a trustee of Vassar College from 1947-1956. He donated a number of rare books and works of art to Vassar. He died on 12 October 1973.
Scope and Content Note
Leaves of incunabula collected by Francis Fitz Randolph.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Printed Leaves Collection
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Printing--Specimens; Printing--Europe--History; Incunabula--Specimens
Document Types:
Incunabula
VCL Categories
Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2015.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Francis Fitz Randolph.
Series List
- Series I. Germany
- Series II. France
- Series III. Switzerland
- Series IV. Belgium
- Series V. Netherlands
- Series VI. Unknown
Container List
- Series I. Germany
  - Author and title unknown. Augsburg: Johann Schüssler, 1472. (1.1)
  - Author and title unknown. Augsburg: Johann Schüssler, 1472. (1.2)
  - Leo I, Pope. Sermones de sanctis. Augsburg: Monastery of SS. Ulrich and Afra, 1474. Hain 16130; Goff L-154. (1.3)
  - Author and title unknown. Augsburg: Günther Zainer, 1476. (1.4)
  - Author and title unknown. Augsburg: Johann Wiener, 1477. (1.5)
  - Author and title unknown. Augsburg: Anton Sorg, ca. 1482. (1.6)
  - Breviarium Pataviense. Augsburg: Erhard Ratdolt, 1490. Hain 3875. (1.7)
  - Author and title unknown [an herbal?]. Augsburg: Anton Sorg, 1497. (1.8)
  - Speculum humanae salvationis. German. Augsburg: Johann Schönsperger, 1500. Hain 14940; Goff S-669 (1.9)
  - Jacobus de Clusa. Sermones notabiles et formales de precipuis festiuitatibus celebribus per anni circulum tam de tempore quam de sanctis. Blaubeuren: Conrad Mancz, ca. 1475-1478. Hain 9330; Goff J-39. (1.10)
  - Guilelmus Peraldus. Summa de virtutibus et vitiis. Cologne: Heinrich Quentell, 1479. Hain 12387; Goff P-84. (1.11)
  - Speculum exemplorum. Cologne: Johann Koelhoff, the Elder, 1485. Hain 14916; Goff S-652. (1.12)
  - Vincent Ferrer. Sermones de tempore et de sanctis. Cologne: Heinrich Quentell, 1485. Hain 7001; Goff F-129. (1.13)
  - Author and title unknown. Esslingen: Conrad Fyner, 1477. (1.14)
  - Augustine. De civitate Dei. Freiburg im Bresigau: Kilian Fischer, 1494. Hain 2068; Goff A-1246. (1.15)
  - Hortus sanitatis. Mainz: Jacob Meydenbach, 1491. Hain 8944; Goff H-486. (1.16)
  - Schatzbehalter der wahren Reichtümer des Heils. Nuremberg: Anton Koberger, 1491. Hain 14507; Goff S-306. (1.17)
  - Parreut, Johannes. Exercationes veteris artis. Nuremberg: Friedrich Creussner, 1494. Hain 12424; Goff P-121. (1.18)
  - Author and title unknown. Nuremberg: Georg Stuchs, ca. 1496. (1.19)
  - Nider, Johannes. Praeceptorium divinae legis. Reutlingen: Michel Greyff, not after 1479. Hain 11781; Goff N-203. (1.20)
  - Henricus de Segusio. Summa Hostiensis. Speier: Georgius de Spira, 1478. Hain 8962; Goff H-44. (1.21)
  - [Vinac, Hugo de Prato Florido?. Sermones dominicales super evangelia et epistolas.?] Strasbourg: Georg Husner, ca. 1478. Hain 8996. (1.22)
  - Balbi, Giovanni. Catholicon. Strasbourg: Printer of the 1483 Jordanus de Quedlinburg (Georg Husner), not after 1483. Hain 2252; Goff B-24. (1.23)
  - Herolt, Johann. Liber discipuli de eruditione Christifidelium. Strasbourg: Jacob Eber, ca. 1483. Hain 8518; Goff H-93. (1.24)
  - Bible. German. 1488. Strasbourg: Johann Grüninger, 1485. Hain 3138; Goff B-633. (1.25)
  - Sermones quadragesimales Thesauri novi. Strasbourg: Printer of the 1483 Vitas Patrum, 1485. Copinger 5431; Goff P-503. (1.26)
  - Bible. Latin. Vulgate. 1489. Strasbourg: Johann Prüss, 1489. Hain 3104; Goff B-588. (1.27)
  - Bible. Latin. Vulgate. 1489. Strasbourg: Johann Prüss, 1489. Hain 3104; Goff B-588. (1.28)
  - Paratus. Sermones de tempore et de sanctis. Strasbourg: Martin Flach, ca. 1490. Hain 12404; Goff P-100. (1.29)
  - Brant, Sebastian. Narrenschiff. Latin. Strasbourg: Johann Grüninger, 1497. Hain 3749; Goff B-1089. (1.30)
  - Terence. Works. 1499. Strasbourg: Johann Grüninger, 1499. Hain 15432; Goff T-101. (1.31)
  - Brunschwig, Hieronymus. Kleines Destillierbuch. Strasbourg: Johann Grüninger, 1500. Hain 4021; Goff B-1227. (1.32)
  - Cyprian. Works. 1486. Stuttgart: Printer of the Erwählung Maximilians, ca. 1486. Hain 5895; Goff C-1014. (1.33)
  - Paulus Scriptor. Lectura in Johannem Duns Scotum super libro primo Sententiarum. Tübingen: Johann Otmar, 1498. Hain 12493; Goff P-206. (1.34)
  - Jacobus de Voragine. Legenda aurea. Ulm: Johann Zainer, ca. 1481. Copinger 6389; Goff J-100. (1.35)
  - Gart der Gesundheit. Ulm: Conrad Dinckmut, 1487. Hain 8952; Goff G-103. (1.36)
- Series II. France
  - Bartholomaeus Anglicus. De proprietatibus rerum. Lyons: Nicolaus Philippi and Marcus Reinhart, 1480. Hain 2500; Goff B-132. (1.37)
  - Gregory IX. Decretales. Lyons: Johann Siber, ca. 1485. Reichling 1746. (1.38)
  - Gorris, Guillermus. Scotus pauperum. Lyons: Guillaume Balsarin, ca. 1487. Reichling 197; Pellechet 5281; Goff G-324. (1.39)
  - Balbi, Giovanni. Catholicon. Lyons: Jean Du Pré, 1489. Hain 2260. (1.40)
  - Gritsch, Johannes. Quadragesimale. Lyons: Guillaume Balsarin, ca. 1490. Hain 8062; Goff G-505. (1.41)
  - Orbellis, Petrus de. Sermones hortuli conscientiae. Lyons: Engelhardt Schultis, 1491. Hain 13627; Goff O-81. (1.42)
  - Bricot, Thomas. Textus abbreviatus in cursum totius physices et metaphysicorum Aristotelis. Lyons: Janon Carcain, 1495. Hain 3973; Goff B-1204. (1.43)
  - Leonardus de Utino. Sermones floridi de tempore. Lyons: Johannes Trechsel, 1496. Hain 16139; Goff L-142. (1.44)
  - Cato, Dionysius. Disticha de moribus. Lyons: Jean de Vingle, 1497. Hain 4713; Goff C-295. (1.45)
  - Auctores octo. Lyons: Mathias Huss, 1498. Reichling 1679. (1.46)
  - Bartholomaeus Anglicus. De proprietatibus rerum. French. Lyons: Jean Dyamantier, 1500. Hain 2519; Goff B-149. (1.47)
  - Armand de Belvézer. De declaratione difficilium terminorum tam theologiae quam philosophiae ac logicae. Lyons: Nicolaus Wolff, 1500. Hain 1796; Goff A-1058. (1.48)
  - Author and title unknown [possibly Temesvári Pelbárt’s Sermones Pomerii de sanctis]. Lyons: Johann Clein, ca. 1500. (1.49)
  - Gregory of Rimini. Lectura super primum librum Sententiarum. Paris: Louis Martineau, 1482. Hain 1645; Goff G-480. (1.50)
  - Guilelmus Hilacensis. Sermones super orationem dominicam. Paris: Ulrich Gering and Berthold Rembolt, 1494. Hain 8219; Goff G-635. (1.51)
  - Aristotle. Nicomachean ethics. Paris: Johannes Higman and Wolfgang Hopyl, 1497. Hain 1761; Goff A-991. (1.52)
  - Catholic Church. Missal Traiectense (Utrecht). Paris: Johann Higman, and Wolfgang Hopyl, 1497. Hain 11434; Goff M-729. (1.53)
  - Catholic Church. Missal Traiectense (Utrecht). Paris: Johann Higman, and Wolfgang Hopyl, 1497. Hain 11434; Goff M-729. (1.54)
  - Faure, Jean. Breviarium super Codicem. Paris: André Bocard, 1499. Copinger 2399. (1.55)
  - Gesta Romanorum. Paris: André Bocard for Jean Petit, 1499. Hain-Copinger 7752; Goff G-297. (1.56)
  - Gaguin, Robert. Compendium de origine et gestis Francorum. Paris: Thielman Kerver, for Durand Gerlier and Jean Petit, 1500. Hain 7413; Goff G-15. (1.57)
  - Maillardus, Oliverius. Sermones de adventu. Sermones dominicales. Quadragesimales. Paris: Philippe Pigouchet, 1500. Hain 10516; Goff M-74. (1.58)
- Series III. Switzerland
  - Meffret. Sermones de tempore et de sanctis, sive, Hortulus reginae. Basel: Nikolaus Kessler, ca. 1488? Hain 11000; Goff M-446. (1.59)
  - Guillermus, Parisiensis. Postilla super epistolas et evangelia. Basel: Michael Furter, ca. 1495. Hain 8250. (1.60)
  - Author and title unknown. Basel: Michael Furter, 1495. (1.61)
  - Petrarca, Francesco. Works. 1496. Basel: Johannes Amerbach, 1496. Hain 12749; Goff P-365. (1.62)
  - Konrad, von Halberstadt. Concordantiae bibliorum. Basel: Johann Froben and Johann Petri, 1496. Hain 5633; Goff C-853. (1.63)
  - Brant, Sebastian. Narrenschiff. Latin. Basel: Johann Bergmann, de Olpe, 1497. Hain 3746[or 3750]]; Goff B-1086 [or B-1090]. (1.64)
  - Jerome. Correspondence. Basel: Nicolaus Kesler, 1497. Hain 8565; Goff H-176. (1.65)
- Belgium
  - Ludolphus de Saxonia. Tboeck vanden leven Jhesu Christi. Antwerp: Claes Leeu, 1488. Hain 10049; Goff L-355. (1.66)
  - Caracciolo, Roberto. Sermones de laudibus sanctorum. Antwerp: Gerard Leeu, 1490. Hain 4481; Goff C-149. (1.67)
  - Vinac, Hugo de Prato Florido. Sermones dominicales super evangelia et epistolas. Louvain: Johann de Paderborn (Westphalia), 1484. Hain 9008; Goff H-510. (1.68)
- Series V. Netherlands
  - Raymond of Sabunde. Theologia naturalis, sive, liber creaturarum. Deventer: Richardus Pafraet, not after 1485. Hain 14067; Goff R-32. (1.69)
  - Jacobus de Voragine. Legenda aurea. Dutch. Utrecht: Johann Veldener, 1480. Copinger 6510; Goff J-144. (1.70)
  - Author and title unknown [Bonaventure?]. Zwolle: Unknown press [Pieter van Os or John de Vollenhoe?], 1479. (1.71)
  - Bonaventure. Tractatus de profectu religiosorum. Zwolle: Pieter van Os, ca. 1495. Copinger 1149. (1.72)
- Series VI. Unknown
  - Author and title unknown. Place unknown [Paris or Venice?]: Printer unknown [André Bocard or Bernardinus Venetus], ca. 1499. (1.73)